<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title> - Organization</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/categories/organization/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/categories/organization/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>GRANTS PASS EMPLOYEE ASSOCIATION CONSTITUTION</title>
        <published>2024-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/constitution/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/constitution/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/constitution/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-1&quot;&gt;Article 1 - Name&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-2&quot;&gt;Article 2 - Affiliation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-3&quot;&gt;Article 3 - Objective&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-4&quot;&gt;Article 4 - Membership and Dues&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-5&quot;&gt;Article 5 - Meetings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-6&quot;&gt;Article 6 - Officers, Nominations and Elections&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-7&quot;&gt;Article 7 - Duties of Officers and Executive Board&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-8-section-b&quot;&gt;Article 8 - Fragments&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;constitution&#x2F;#article-9&quot;&gt;Article 9 - Amendments&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-1-name&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 1 - NAME&lt;a id=&quot;article-1&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the organization shall be the City of Grants Pass Employee Association, Local Number ____ of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-2-affiliation&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 2 - AFFILIATION&lt;a id=&quot;article-2&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local union shall be affiliated with the Oregon AFSCME Council 75 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees;  the Oregon state organization of the AFL-CIO; and the Southern REgion central body of the AFL-CIO.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-3-objective&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 3 - OBJECTIVE&lt;a id=&quot;article-3&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objectives of this local union shall be to carry out on a local basis the objectives of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-4-membership-and-dues&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 4 - MEMBERSHIP AND DUES&lt;a id=&quot;article-4&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a&quot;&gt;SECTION A&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All persons regularly employed by the City of Grants Pass are eligible for membership in this local union, subject to the requirements of the Constitution of the International Union.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b&quot;&gt;SECTION B&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application for membership shall be made on a standard application form.  Unless such form includes a valid authorization for payroll deduction of dues, the application shall be accompanied by the current month&#x27;s dues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c&quot;&gt;SECTION C&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the ratification of the first contract, the monthly membership dues of the local union shall be 1% of each employee&#x27;s base salary or $15.00, whichever is greater, not to exceed $60.00 per member, per month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d&quot;&gt;SECTION D&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membership dues shall be payable monthly, in advance to the local secretary-treasurer and in any event shall be paid not later than the 15th day of the month in which they become due.  Any member who fails to pay dues by the 15th day of the month in which they become due shall be considered delinquent, and upon failure to pay dues for two successive months shall stand suspended.  Provided, however, that any person who is paying dues through a system of regular payroll deduction shall for so long as such person continues to pay through such deduction method, be considered in good standing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e&quot;&gt;SECTION E&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member suspended under the above section may be reinstated to membership in the local on payment of all arrearages plus the current month&#x27;s dues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-5-meetings&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 5 - MEETINGS&lt;a id=&quot;article-5&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-1&quot;&gt;SECTION A&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular meetings of this local union shall be held once each month, at a time and place to be fixed by the membership or the local executive board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-1&quot;&gt;SECTION B&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special meetings may be called by the local president, the local executive board, or by petition filed with the president and signed by 20% of the members of the local union.  Special meetings may also be called by the International President or by an authorized representative of the International President.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-1&quot;&gt;SECTION C&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quorum for meetings of this local union shall be 20% of the members.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-6-officers-nominations-and-elections&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 6 - OFFICERS, NOMINATIONS AND ELECTIONS&lt;a id=&quot;article-6&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-2&quot;&gt;SECTION A&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officers of this local union shall be a president a vice president, a secretary and a treasurer.  These four officers shall constitute the local union executive board.  In addition, there shall be elected three members who shall serve as trustees.  The trustees shall be elected to three-year terms of office, except that in the initial election, one shall be elected for a one-year term, one for a two-year term, and one for a three-year term.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-2&quot;&gt;SECTION B&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominations shall be made at a regular or special meeting of the local union.  At least fifteen days advance notice shall be given to the membership prior to the nomination meeting.  A nominating committee may be appointed or elected to make nominations, but whether or not such nominating committee is used, nominations shall be permitted from the floor at the nomination meeting.  All regular elections shall be held on the second Tuesday in May of each year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-2&quot;&gt;SECTION C&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible for office, a member must be in good standing for one year immediately preceding the election, except in the initial election held in this local union;  provided, however, that no retired member shall be a candidate for office.  For a member who is transferred or promoted into this local union from another AFSCME local, this requirement shall be satisfied if such member&#x27;s combined membership in good standing in both locals is one year at the time of the election.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-1&quot;&gt;SECTION D&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers shall be elected by secret ballot vote, and the balloting shall be conducted so as to afford to all members a reasonable opportunity to vote.  At least fifteen days advance notice shall be given the membership prior to the holding of the election.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e-1&quot;&gt;SECTION E&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All matters concerning nominations and elections in this local union shall be subject to the provisions of Appendix D, entitled Elections Code, of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.afscme.org&#x2F;about&#x2F;governance&#x2F;document&#x2F;2022-International-Constitution-English.pdf&quot;&gt;International Union Constitution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-f&quot;&gt;SECTION F&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-f&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vacancies in office shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term by majority vote of those members present at the next regular meeting from the date the office is vacated, except in the case of President, in which the order of attrition shall take place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-g&quot;&gt;SECTION G&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-g&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every officer shall, upon assuming office, subscribe to the Obligation of an Officer contained in Appendix B of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.afscme.org&#x2F;about&#x2F;governance&#x2F;document&#x2F;2022-International-Constitution-English.pdf&quot;&gt;International Union Constitution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, ___________________, promise and pledge that I will perform faithfully and with honor the duties of the office which I now assume in the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees.
I pledge to fight for a society where all workers can seek economic and social justice through participation in their union and our democracy.
I will work for these goals by organizing unorganized workers, mobilizing workers to participate in the political process, and fighting to gain and defend the best possible working standards through contracts and legislation.
I acknowledge that it is a privilege to serve in this office and I promise that I will deliver to my successor in office all books, papers and other property of this union which are in my possession at
the close of my official term.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-7-duties-of-officers-and-executive-board&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 7 - DUTIES OF OFFICERS AND EXECUTIVE BOARD&lt;a id=&quot;article-7&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-3&quot;&gt;SECTION A&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President shall:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preside at all meetings of the local union and of the Executive Board;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a member of all committees except election committees;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Countersign all checks drawn against the funds of the local; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report periodically to the membership regarding the progress and standing of the local and regarding the President&#x27;s official acts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-3&quot;&gt;SECTION B&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vice President shall:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist the President in the work of the President&#x27;s office;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the absence of the President or in the President&#x27;s inability to serve, preside at all meetings and perform all duties otherwise performed by the President; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon approval by the local executive board, be authorized to act as cosigner of checks drawn on the local funds in place of either the President or the Treasurer.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-3&quot;&gt;SECTION C&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary shall:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a record of the proceedings of all membership meetings and of all Executive Board meetings;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carry on the official correspondence of the local, except as the Executive Board may direct otherwise; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform such other duties as the Executive Board may require.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor&#x27;s Note: Page 4 containing the conclusion of Article 7 and the beginning of Article 8 is missing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fragment-of-article-8&quot;&gt;Fragment of ARTICLE 8&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;members or group of members or other person or persons shall have the power to act on behalf of or otherwise bind the local union except to the extent specifically authorized in writing by the President of the local union or by the Executive Board of the local union.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-4&quot;&gt;SECTION C&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules contained in the current edition of Robert&#x27;s Rules of Order, Newly Revised shall govern this local union in all cases to which they are applicable and in which they are not inconsistent with this Constitution and special rules of this local union or of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-9-amendments&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 9 - AMENDMENTS&lt;a id=&quot;article-9&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Constitution may be amended, revised, or otherwise changed by a majority vote of the members voting on such proposed change and such change shall take effect only upon written approval of the International President.  Proposed amendments to this Constitution must be made at a regular or special meeting of the local union and read and voted on at a subsequent meting of the local union, adequate and proper notice having been given to the membership prior to the date of which the vote is taken.  A written copy of the proposed amendment shall be furnished to every eligible voter at the meeting at which the vote is taken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>CITY OF GRANTS PASS EMPLOYEE ASSOCIATION BYLAWS</title>
        <published>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/bylaws/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/bylaws/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/bylaws/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-1&quot;&gt;Article 1 - Name and Objective&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-2&quot;&gt;Article 2 - Membership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-3&quot;&gt;Article 3 - Dues&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-4&quot;&gt;Article 4 - General Organization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-5&quot;&gt;Article 5 - Committees&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-6&quot;&gt;Article 6 - Election of Officers and Voting Procedure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-7&quot;&gt;Article 7 - Meetings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-8&quot;&gt;Article 8 - Limitations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#article-9&quot;&gt;Article 9 - Amendments&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io&#x2F;bylaws&#x2F;#exhibit-a&quot;&gt;Exhibit A - Optional Dues Language&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-1-name-and-objective&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 1 - NAME AND OBJECTIVE&lt;a id=&quot;article-1&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-1-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the organization shall be the City of Grants Pass Employee Association (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Association&quot;) and it shall be a non-profit, non-partisan, independent employee affiliation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-1-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose and objectives of the Association are as follows:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To improve employment relations for the betterment of its members with the City of Grants Pass;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To represent its members in all matters relating to employment including grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours of employment, conditions of work and benefits;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To foster co-operation between the association members and department representatives of the City of Grants Pass;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide formal collective bargaining contract administration; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide formal collective bargaining representation for its members.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-1-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Association may receive and hold money and property, both real and personal, by gift, contributions or otherwise, and disperse any funds for the benefit of its members and generally do and perform all acts incident to or appropriate to the execution of the above stated purposes and objectives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-2-membership&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 2 - MEMBERSHIP&lt;a id=&quot;article-2&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-1&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-2-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular membership is limited to employees of the City of Grants Pass whose salary or wages are received from the City of Grants Pass.  Elected officials, department heads, mid-management and confidential employees shall not be eligible for membership.  Exception is made for those individuals who have a bona fide religious tenet which prohibits membership in such an organization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All regular members of the Association shall have the following benefits:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representation in collective bargaining;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of Association funds toward collective bargaining;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representation in grievances against the City of Grants Pass;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting privileges; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participation in setting Association policies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-1&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-2-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membership in this Association shall terminate as follows:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon the death of a member;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon termination of employment with the City of Grants Pass whether by voluntary termination or retirement; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon transferring to a job position that would make the member ineligible as stated in Article 2, Section A above.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-1&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-2-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All members of this Association shall apply for membership and become members of any Union contracted to represent this Association and further, will maintain such membership to the extent to which membership may be required to be maintained pursuant the laws of the State of Oregon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-2-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Association, its officers, representatives and members shall recognize, observe and be bound by the provisions of these Bylaws and the Association&#x27;s contract with the City of Grants Pass and&#x2F;or Union, if applicable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-3-dues&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 3 - DUES&lt;a id=&quot;article-3&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Association dues are not contemplated in these Bylaws.  See Exhibit A, a copy of which has been attached hereto, for optional dues language.  Follow the procedure set forth in Article 9 for inclusion of this language herein.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-4-general-organization&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 4 - GENERAL ORGANIZATION&lt;a id=&quot;article-4&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-2&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The governing body of this Association shall be the Executive Board which consists of the President, Vice President, Secretary and Treasurer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-2&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any regular member in good standing shall be eligible for office in this Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-2&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon the initial inception of these Bylaws, elections shall be held for each officer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial President and Secretary shall hold office for a term of one (1) year and thereafter, shall hold office for a term of two (2) years, until the election and installation of their successors, unless recalled from office.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-1&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Trustees shall be elected by a majority vote of the membership.  One shall be elected for a one-year term, one for a two-year term and one for a three-year term.  Thereafter, each shall be elected for a three-year term of office.  The sole purpose of the Trustees is to make or to cause to be made, at least semi-annually, an audit of the finances of the Association, the results of which shall be reported to the membership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e&quot;&gt;Section E&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers of this Association can be recalled from office for the following reasons:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acts which would discredit the Association and prevent the Association from carrying out the best interest of its members;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure to remain a full member in good standing in the Association; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure to attend any three (3) consecutive meetings of the Association or Executive Board unless a majority of the Executive Board rules that there are extenuating circumstances warranting continuance of membership on the Executive Board.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-f&quot;&gt;Section F&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-f&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In performance of its duties and responsibilities, the Executive Board shall:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish committees and a group representative system to assist in bargaining practices and the planning and development of Association policies, programs and operations;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruit and retain the highest possible percentage of eligible employees as members of the Association;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide services to ensure that adequate representation is afforded to members with respect to employment conditions and benefits;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide communications to keep the membership informed of activities of Association.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hear and act on member appeals submitted to the Executive Board;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make such studies as are necessary for the development of policies, programs and projects of the Association;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In May of each year, plan a preliminary budget of estimated income and expenditures to implement the operations and programs of the Association for the succeeding fiscal year;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish fiscal policies for the expenditure, deposit and investment of the funds in the Association;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a meeting schedule and inform the general membership of the dates, times, locations and agendas of its meetings.  Minutes of the meetings shall be made available to the general membership; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide for an annual audit and report on the books and accounts of the Association.  The annual audit shall be completed prior to the installation of new officers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-g&quot;&gt;Section G&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-g&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Executive Board shall have the authority to enter into purchasing agreements or contracts provided, however, that no debt shall be incurred which would impair the operations and solvency of the Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-h&quot;&gt;Section H&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-h&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All grievance duties shall be the responsibility of the Executive Board.  A grievance shall be defined as any dispute between labor and management cognizable under any labor contract between the Association and the City of Grants Pass.  In lieu of and in addition to the steps set forth any labor contract, the Executive Board will operate under the following rules:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The member requesting assistance from the Association shall appear, in writing, to the Executive Board, who will then determine by majority vote, the validity of the grievance, after due investigation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appeal of the Executive Board&#x27;s decision may be made to the Association at a special or regular meeting called by the aggrieved as set forth in Article 7, Section C.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-i&quot;&gt;Section I&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-i&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All legislative duties shall be the responsibility of the Executive Board.  The Executive Board shall ensure that the aims and interest of the membership are furthered through the education of the public, generally, and elected representatives specifically.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-j&quot;&gt;Section J&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-j&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President of the Association shall preside at all meetings of the Association.  In the absence of the President, the Vice President shall preside.  The President shall be the executive head of the Association and the chairman of the Executive Board.  Together with the Vice President, Secretary and Treasurer, the President may sign orders and checks lawfully drawn.  The President shall enforce strict observance of the Bylaws of the Association and shall have general supervision of the other officers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President shall discharge on behalf of the Association such duties as may be imposed upon him&#x2F;her applicable by law, including the execution and filing of any reports to the Federal or State authorities and the President shall cause to be maintained by the Association such records as the law requires to kept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-k&quot;&gt;Section K&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-k&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vice President shall assist the President in such a manner as the President may determine.  In the absence of the President, the Vice President shall preside at meetings of the Association and the Executive Board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-l&quot;&gt;Section L&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-l&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Treasurer shall perform the following duties on behalf of the Association:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive all money due the Association, from whatever source, and disburse the same only by check signed by him&#x2F;her and the President or Vice President;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and keep current and accurate records of members&#x27; dues, payments, assessments and all other financial transactions;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be prepared to exhibit receipts and vouchers upon the audit of the Association&#x27;s books; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present to the membership at each regular meeting an accounting of the past month&#x27;s financial transactions to provide accountability and justification of any disbursements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-m&quot;&gt;Section M&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-m&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary shall perform the following duties on behalf of the Association:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain and have custody of all documents, records, books and papers belonging to the Association and&#x2F;or required by law expect as provided elsewhere in these Bylaws;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep an accurate record of the meetings of the Association and the Executive Board;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attest all official documents with his&#x2F;her signature;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct the correspondence of the Association promptly; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the official list of members of the organization in an accurate and current manner, including listings of retired members and members not in good standing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-n&quot;&gt;Section N&lt;a id=&quot;article-4-section-n&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each member of the Executive Board is required to attend all meetings of the Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-5-committees&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 5 - COMMITTEES&lt;a id=&quot;article-5&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-3&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Association shall nominate and appoint by a majority vote at any regular meeting of the Association of the following standing committees.  Each committee, at its first meeting, shall nominate and appoint a committee chairperson by a majority vote.  If a matter arises in which a particular committee is not established, or the matter is not under the responsibility of an appointed committee, it shall be the President&#x27;s responsibility or the President&#x27;s designee to represent the Association in such matters.  The following committees may be established:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - It shall be the responsibility of the President or an appointee of the President to contact all potential non-members of the Association for the purpose of recruitment;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salaries, Wages and Benefits (SWB)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - It shall be the responsibility of the SWB committee to represent the Association in all bargaining duties or negotiations involving salaries, wages and benefits as directed by the Executive Board and a majority vote of the members present at any Association meeting where negotiation matters are discussed.  The SWB Committee shall keep the members of the Association apprised of the status of negotiations through regular or special meetings and written memorandum to the Association;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit Committee&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - It shall be the responsibility of this committee to conduct a yearly audit of the City of Grants Pass Employee Association books in January of each year and provide a report of such to the Executive Board; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget Committee&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - It shall be the responsibility of this committee to prepare a preliminary budget during May of each year for review and approval by the Executive Board.  Said Budget shall be presented to the Executive Board no later than June 15 of the year that it is prepared.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-3&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No committee may act on its own accord or commit the Association to a course of action without the approval of the Executive Board and a majority vote of the members.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-3&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President, with a majority of the Executive Board, may appoint &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; committees as needed.  &lt;em&gt;Ad hoc&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; committees shall not succeed the term of the appointing President but may be re-appointed by succeeding Presidents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-2&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-5-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each committee chair shall submit the proposed committee program for the year to the Executive Board for review and approval.  The Association budget shall make specific line item provisions for committee activities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-6-election-of-officers-and-voting-procedure&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 6 - ELECTION OF OFFICERS AND VOTING PROCEDURE&lt;a id=&quot;article-6&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-4&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A President, Vice President, Secretary, and Treasurer shall be elected for a term of two (2) years.  The position of Vice President shall be the candidate receiving the second majority of the votes with respect to the votes of the Association for President.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-4&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any nomination shall be certified to by the candidate that the candidate will serve if elected.  The Secretary shall give written notice to the Association members, whether by email or public posting, of any nomination, election procedure or deadline date.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-4&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elections shall be by secret written ballot.  There shall be no voting by proxy in the election of Association officers.  The candidate receiving a majority of the ballots cast shall be declared elected.  If no candidate receives a majority of the ballots cast, the balloting shall continue through a run-off election in which only the two candidates receiving the greatest number of votes shall participate until there is a majority, eliminating the candidate receiving the lowest number of votes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-3&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ballots will be available to each member of the Association in good standing at least fifteen (15) days prior to the annual meeting in the form prescribed herein.  Association members in good standing may then cast their vote for the candidate of their choice and deliver their ballots to a locked and sealed box, the location of which shall be determined by the Executive Board.  Votes may be placed in the ballot box from the time of delivering the ballots to members until (1) hour prior to the annual meeting, at which time the Secretary will bring the ballots, unopened, to the annual meeting to be counted.  At the annual meeting, members who have not yet cast their votes will be given the opportunity to do so.  In the event of a run-off, ties will be broken by secret ballot cast by a majority of the members present at the annual meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each ballot shall contain the name of every candidate, showing the office the nominee is running for.  Each member shall be furnished a ballot and two envelopes.  One envelope shall be plain and one shall contain the printed name of the member.  Members shall insert the ballot in the plain envelope and insert the plain envelope in the envelope with his&#x2F;her name thereon.  The member will then sign by the printed name with his&#x2F;her signature and place the ballot in the ballot box.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e-1&quot;&gt;Section E&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of counting of ballots, the Secretary and Treasurer, in the presence of a volunteer member, shall open the locked box and as each envelope is removed, verify that the name thereon is that of a member in good standing and eligible to vote.  The Secretary, Treasurer and volunteer member shall then open and count the ballots contained in the unmarked envelopes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-f-1&quot;&gt;Section F&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-f&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary and Treasurer shall sign the tally sheets which constitute the official results of the election.  Ballots shall be preserved by the Secretary and Treasurer for one (1) month following an election.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-g-1&quot;&gt;Section G&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-g&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers shall be installed by June 30th and shall take office immediately upon their installation to serve until their successors are installed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-h-1&quot;&gt;Section H&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-h&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an office becomes vacant by reason of death, resignation, promotion or recall, the members shall elect a successor for the remainder of the current year by majority vote of those present at the next regular meeting from the date the office is vacated, expect in the case of President, in which the order of attrition shall take place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-i-1&quot;&gt;Section I&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-i&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case that the President shall be unable to complete a term of office, he&#x2F;she shall be succeeded by the Vice President, Secretary and Treasurer, in that order.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-j-1&quot;&gt;Section J&lt;a id=&quot;article-6-section-j&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Votes on initiation fees, increase in membership dues, offer for settlement of collection bargaining negotiations, reinstatement fees, special assessments and recall of an officer shall be by secret written ballot and follow the methods set forth in this Article 6, except that the time limits shall apply to the next scheduled meeting instead of the annual meeting.  All other votes of regular Association business may be, at the option of the presiding officer, by voice or show of hands during a regular or special meeting.  There shall be no voting by proxy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-7-meetings&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 7 - MEETINGS&lt;a id=&quot;article-7&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-5&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular meetings of this Association shall be held monthly, at a day and time determined by a vote of the members present at any annual, regular or special meeting.  The place will be determined by the President and will be posted, along with the time, at a public location and shall notify the members of the Association through email.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-5&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An annual meeting shall be held by the second Tuesday in May or at a time and place determined by the Association and announced at least one month in advance of the meeting.  The annual meeting shall be for the purpose of electing officers of the Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-5&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special meetings may be called in three ways:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By a majority vote of the Executive Board;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By an aggrieved member for the purpose of appeal to a decision by the Executive Board regarding any grievance filed by said member; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By twenty percent (20%) of the members in good standing who petition the Executive Board to call a special meeting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any request for a special meeting shall be in writing and shall specifically state what business shall be included on the agenda and no other business shall be conducted at that meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shall be the responsibility of the Executive Board to notify, in writing, all members of the Association of the time and place of the meeting, together with a copy of the agenda, at least forty-eight (48) hours prior to the meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-4&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quorum for any meeting of this Association shall be twenty percent (20%) of the Association members in good standing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e-2&quot;&gt;Section E&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise stated herein, all meetings shall be governed by Roberts Rules of Order.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-f-2&quot;&gt;Section F&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-f&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member who is present at any meeting of the Association at which action on any Association matter is taken shall be presumed to have assented to the holdings of the meeting and action taken unless his&#x2F;her dissent or objection is entered on the minutes of the meeting or unless he&#x2F;she forwards such dissent by certified mail to the Secretary or Treasurer of the Association immediately after the adjournment of the meeting.  Such right of dissent shall not apply to a member who voted in favor of such action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-g-2&quot;&gt;Section G&lt;a id=&quot;article-7-section-g&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agenda of Association meetings shall include:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll call of the Board;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approval of Minutes;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treasurer&#x27;s Report;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Union Report;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc. Reports;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additions to the Agenda;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old Business;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Business;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous; and&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjournment.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-8-limitations&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 8 - LIMITATIONS&lt;a id=&quot;article-8&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-6&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No officer, director, member or employee shall take any action on behalf of or in the name of the Association which is not compatible with its objectives, policies or programs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-6&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No member of the Association shall be discriminated against because of race, national origin, sex, political or religious opinions or affiliations.  Nothing in this Section shall be construed to protect any member who advocates the overthrow of the United States Government by force or violence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-6&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No member shall be denied the right to address the Executive Board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-5&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total budgetary allotment for any activity shall not be exceeded except by approval of the Executive Board and upon transfer from other allotments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-e-3&quot;&gt;Section E&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-e&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No solicitations or contracts shall be made in the name of the Association without approval of the Executive Board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-f-3&quot;&gt;Section F&lt;a id=&quot;article-8-section-f&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No assessments shall be levied without approval of the membership at an annual or special meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;article-9-amendments&quot;&gt;ARTICLE 9 - AMENDMENTS&lt;a id=&quot;article-9&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-7&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;article-9-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bylaws of the Association may be amended by a majority vote of those present at any general membership meeting provided that notice of such meeting set forth at least fifteen (15) days prior to the meeting, stating such request or intent for amendment and that a vote will be taken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-7&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;article-9-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any proposed amendment to the Bylaws shall be presented to the Secretary in writing not less than twenty (20) days before an Association meeting.  The Secretary shall supply copies of the proposed amendment to each member of the Association and Executive Board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;exhibit-a-optional-dues-language&quot;&gt;EXHIBIT A - OPTIONAL DUES LANGUAGE&lt;a id=&quot;exhibit-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-a-8&quot;&gt;Section A&lt;a id=&quot;exhibit-a-section-a&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dues for regular members of this Association shall be set by a majority vote of the Association at whatever level is necessary to maintain membership in a Union or to retain private legal counsel.  All dues reflecting the amount necessary to maintain membership in the Union or private legal counsel will be paid by the Association to the Union or law firm within ten (10) days of the receipt thereof.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-b-8&quot;&gt;Section B&lt;a id=&quot;exhibit-a-section-b&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dues shall be payable bi-weekly by payroll deduction where this is available or may be paid quarterly, semi-annually or annually in advance to the Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-c-7&quot;&gt;Section C&lt;a id=&quot;exhibit-a-section-c&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members on an authorized non-paid leave of absence from their employment may be excused from paying dues.  Such person excused from paying dues shall retain full membership rights and shall be automatically reinstated to active status upon their return from such leave.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-d-6&quot;&gt;Section D&lt;a id=&quot;exhibit-a-section-d&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members who fail to pay their dues or assessments within 10 days of the due date shall be notified of such delinquency by the Secretary or Treasurer of the Association and will be automatically suspended and lose their good standing if payment is not made within sixty (60) days following such notification.  Delinquent and suspended members are not entitled to voice or vote in the Association.  Fair-share members of the Association shall not be entitled to voice or vote in the Association.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Organization</title>
        <published>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/organization/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/organization/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/organization/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;vision&quot;&gt;Vision&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vision statement here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mission&quot;&gt;Mission&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission statement here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;governance&quot;&gt;Governance&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The governing body of the GPEA includes the Executive Board, consisting of the President, Vice President, Secretary and Treasurer, as well as the members who participate in meetings, voicing their priorities and voting on official business.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link to &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;constitution&quot;&gt;Constitution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link to &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;bylaws&quot;&gt;Bylaws&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;meetings&quot;&gt;Meetings&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two forms of official meetings in which all members are free to participate:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General meetings - Regularly scheduled meetings for conducting official GPEA business.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special meetings - Called irregularly by the President, Board or 20% of the membership.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Executive Board may hold closed meetings for discussion of GPEA affairs, but may not conduct official business&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to conduct official business, meetings require a quorum equal to 20% of all members.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established in year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Event Calendar</title>
        <published>2024-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/events/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/events/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/events/">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;calendar.google.com&#x2F;calendar&#x2F;embed?height=600&amp;wkst=1&amp;ctz=America%2FLos_Angeles&amp;bgcolor=%23ffffff&amp;src=NzZiMjM2MWRiZTZjOWZmZjAyZTc2YzhjYmRkM2Y0NDYwZjAwNWU2ZGU0ZDI2YmZiNzBjNzhiZTM4YWNkYjY4N0Bncm91cC5jYWxlbmRhci5nb29nbGUuY29t&amp;color=%23F4511E&quot; style=&quot;border:solid 1px #777&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Volunteers</title>
        <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/volunteers/"/>
        <id>https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/volunteers/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://grantspassemployeeassociation.github.io/volunteers/">&lt;p&gt;The employee association relies on volunteer effort from among our members to provide leadership and organization.  All members are eligible for participation in leadership, as well as support roles in committees.  As a member, we value your input and hope that contribute &lt;em&gt;your&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; talent and ideas to our team.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association has four elected positions, the &lt;em&gt;Executive Officers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, as well as volunteer-based committees.  The GPEA holds elections every 2 years, with the next election scheduled for 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executive Officers represent members by setting negotiating priorities, tactics and strategies, as well as by speaking by on behalf of employees during the formal contract bargaining process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committees help to engage with members to develop our bargaining priorities, and accomplish the hard work of translating employee priorities into potential language amendments for the next contract bargaining agreement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-officers&quot;&gt;Executive Officers&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formal leadership structure of the association is the executive team, composed of four executive officers:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;President&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vice President&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secretary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treasurer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-leadership&quot;&gt;Current Leadership&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#x2F;content&#x2F;erikrose_portrait.png alt=&quot;Erik Rose Portrait&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Erik Rose - President&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Employee Position: GIS Technician II&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Department: Public Works&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Phone: &lt;a href=tel:+15414506112&gt;(541) 450-6112&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=mailto:erose@grantspassoregon.gov&gt;erose@grantspassoregon.gov&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik moved to Grants Pass with a family of five in 2022 to work for the City in the GIS Division. He began volunteering for GPEA in 2023 when he was elected Vice President.  He succeeded to President in 2024 following Christine Westbrook.  Prior to volunteering with GPEA, he served on the Board of the First Alternative Natural Foods Co-op from 2014-2020, including a stint as Treasurer from 2017-2019.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik has a PhD in Environmental Sciences from Oregon State University, a Masters in Public Administration from the Evans School of Public Policy and Governance at the University of Washington, and a Bachelors in Music Composition from the Flora Thorton School of Music at University of Southern California.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Donna Anderson - Vice President&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Employee Position: Department Support Technician&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Department: Fleet&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Phone: &lt;a href=tel:+15414506011&gt;(541) 450-6011&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=mailto:danderson@grantspassoregon.gov&gt;danderson@grantspassoregon.gov&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;James Conway - Secretary&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Employee Position: Economic Development Specialist&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Department: Community Development&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Phone: &lt;a href=tel:+15414506&gt;(541) 450-6&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=mailto:jconway@grantspassoregon.gov&gt;jconway@grantspassoregon.gov&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Vacant - Treasurer&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
